Dhruv Sethi



Mob +91-9212714226

Mail Dhruv Sethi2004@yahoo.co.in

The professional journey started when E-commerce was in embryonic stage. Fortunate to have been a part of its growth story & evolution globally. Cofounding Team member for few of the most popular and successful start-ups such as Jabong, ibibo-Tradus & Floradlite.

An e-commerce industry specialist with close to 15 years of comprehensive experience and knowledge across dimensions of business including managing a business division for profitability, buying and sourcing, category management, assortment planning & merchandising, product development & launches, marketing & promotions, technology, sales, and cost optimization.

Skill Set

- Revenue & Profitability (P&L)
- Sales Planning & Strategy
- Pricing Strategy & Demand Planning
- Assortment & Category Management
- Campaign & Promotion Planning
- Traffic & Keyword Optimization
- Monetization Income
- Startup Specialist

- Marketplace Expert
- Business Alliances
- Key Account Management
- Vendor Development
- Market Intelligence & Research
- Strategy Consulting
- Other Modern Trade Channels
- Process Excellence & Strategy
- Buying & Merchandising Strategy
- Planning & Forecasting
- Inventory & Merchandise Management
- Product Design & Development
- Sourcing & Procurement Planning
- Leadership & Team Management
- Business Strategy & Planning
- Cross Functional Coordination

Career

Flora D'lite – Head Business & Operations (Middle East & India), May 2022 to January 2023

Ferns N Petals – Head Category & Sourcing, October 2017 to April 2022

- KAM Category & Sourcing, Jun 2017 to September 2017

Myntra Jabong – Senior Manager, Category Lead, January 2016 to January 2017

- Category Manager (Marketplace), October 2013 to December 2015

Ibibo / Tradus.com - Category Manager (Buying & Sourcing), April 2013 to October 2013

– Assistant Manager (Buying & Sourcing), April 2011 to April 2013

- Business Development Manager (Marketplace), April 2010 to April 2011

- Business Development Executive (Marketplace), August 2009 to April 2010

Career Summary

Floradlite.com – The role was to lead end to end ownership towards launching of Flora D'lite website and its operations from scratch in Middle East and India, offering a premium yet sophisticated portfolio of gifting across categories for the requirements of both individuals & corporates.

- Achieved GMV of 13 Cr within a span of 10 months by extending geographies starting Oman (Muscat) followed by Bahrain, Qatar, Dubai & India.
- Drove the platform shift from WordPress to Magento followed by billingual & region-specific UIs for enriched customer experience & engagement.
- Set up infrastructure for cold chain, fulfillment center & hubs along with logistics & last mile hyperlocal deliveries.
- Initiated alliances with marketplace channels like Talabat, Akeed, FNP, Bleems, Sharaf DG, etc. leading to break even within 60-90 days.
- Diversified the portfolio to B2B, retailers, hotels, etc. to enhance the top line.
- -P & L management, category & merchandise management, launches & promotions across all platforms.
- -Team building & hiring across regions followed by leadership.

Fnp.com – India's largest gifting company with an annual revenue of 650 Cr and serving in more than 300 retail outlets, followed by its recent foray into global markets in Middle East & South East Asia.

- A proven track record of over achieving top line as well as bottom line during my tenure of 5 years with FNP, managing a portfolio ranging between 120-250 Cr with a two-digit Gross margin.
- Relaunched non-core categories like plants, personalized and chocolates, scaled them up by a 500% growth & towards a double-digit category in crores making them to be considered as a core category within a period of 12 to 24 months.
- Initiated the launch of marketplace model from scratch, starting from SOP's, operation requirement, vendor panels and alliances.
- Added life to stagnant flowers category witnessing a flat 15% YOY growth since previous 5 years, resulting to a growth level of 25-35% which is standard amongst any category within the company.
- Channelized direct sourcing from brands across locations, resulting towards better margins, lower costs & monetized income for campaigns.

Jabong.com – Jabong had been the revolution of fashion in e-commerce during its era, acquired by Myntra Flipkart and now a part of Walmart Inc. My journey started with marketplace and followed by growth in various categories as well as roles. Managed & owned P&L across fashion verticals such as apparel, footwear, accessories, home furnishing, beauty & personal-care and kids.

- Managed a profitable portfolio of 80 Cr with 60% YOY growth, spread across 700 brands & merchants with an active catalog size of 5k+ SKU's.
- Maintained overall in-stock inventory ratio to 74% for entire catalog and 82% for top sellers in JIT model (Marketplace).
- Lead the hybrid model of alliances with existing & new brands by shifting them to marketplace from outright, consignment or SOR basis.

- Private Label development for Marketplace model, focusing towards exclusivity and higher margins.
- Worked closely with marketing team in order to drive sales through SEO, SEM, affiliate marketing, e-mailers & other mediums for the portfolio
 with 76% merchant participation followed by special launches for monetized brands.

Tradus.com – Tradus, nestled under ibibo Web Pvt Ltd, a Naspers Group Company started Indian operations in 2009 as a C2C auctions platform and transformed to fixed price marketplace model. The journey started as a Co-founding team member & the very first in the business as well as category team, fortunate to have launch every second category starting from CDIT, books, fashion & accessories, home, kids, pets etc.

- Managed a portfolio size of 62 Cr with double digit profitability during the era when ecommerce was in nascent phase & onboarding brands to retailing them online was not a cake walk.
- Responsible for retail planning for the category, monitoring of stock /sales plan / maintaining defined stock covers/gross margins, OTB management, range, product mix and line planning for the category as per price, color, trend & design analysis.
- Part of the transition from a customer acquisition model via online auctions to a closed marketplace & lastly an open marketplace.
- Launching long tail categories (600-5k SKU's) on dropship model via APIs on net revenue models.
- Introduced private label as well as white label across categories.
- Onboarding eCommerce players that were a direct competition like flipkart for books, letsbuy for electronics, bigshoebazaar (yebhi) for footwear and other fashion categories, Ngals for nightwear, Tantra for graphic tees, johareez for jewellery, dogspot for pet supplies and many more.

Other Associations

- Visiting Faculty to Management & Design Institutes.

Educational qualifications

- Post Graduation: Master of Fashion Management Fashion Management Studies, NIFT Blore, 2007 2009.
- Graduation: Bachelors of Commerce, Delhi College of Arts & Commerce (Delhi University), 2003-2006.
- Others: Swift C++, NIIT, 2002.

Dhruv Sethi.